Danielle Hoey

Software Engineer

(413) 822-2738 · danianisehoev@gmail.com · Lunenburg, MA · LinkedIn · GitHub · Portfolio

SUMMARY

Software Engineer with experience in full-stack engineering and a passion for front-end engineering. Previous work experience in customer service has made clear the importance of integrity and empathy. A proactive and resourceful problem-solver. Able to thrive in independent, self-managed work while still displaying exceptional communication and interpersonal skills.

SKILLS

Programming Languages - JavaScript | Python | HTML5 | CSS3 | Mongo | Mongoose | JSON

Frameworks - React | Django | NodeJS | Express

Databases - MongoDB, PostgreSQL

Other - RESTful Routing, JSON api, GitHub

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

January 2022 - Present

Harry Potter Trivia Book/Movie Trivia | Javascript, Vanilla Javascript, HTML5, CSS3 | GitHub Repo

- A Wizarding World based trivia game with increasing levels of difficulty. The user will see an appropriate level of difficulty based on their level of knowledge
- Utilized Git control during the production of the application with frequent commits until deployment
- Application created with a mobile-first approach and styled the application using DOM Manipulation and CSS3 with flexbox layouts

What's for Dinner? Recipe Organization App | Express, MongoDB/Mongoose, JSON, Javascript, NodeJS, RESTful Routing | GitHub Repo

- An app to help families decide what to have for dinner. Users can filter the recipes based on their preferences, allergies, and what they have in their fridge
- Utilized Git control during the production of the application with frequent commits until deployment
- Tested routes using Postman to ensure functionality during production

<u>Mock Stock</u> Stock Market Portfolio App | Javascript, ReactJS, Express, NodeJS, MongoDB/Mongoose, API data integration, RESTful Routing, React Bootstrap | GitHub Repos: <u>Front-End</u>, <u>Back-End</u>

- Collaborated with a 3-person team of software engineers in a 2-week sprint to develop an app using MongoDB for the back-end and React for the front-end
- A mock-up of a stock market app that will represent the user's portfolio. The user will be able to see stock holdings, portfolio balance, stock-specific information, and be able to search for current stock data
- The app has full CRUD capabilities in that the user can add new stocks upon purchase, see their portfolio information, update their portfolio upon change to holdings (buy/sell in part), and delete stocks upon sale

[theAlumniNetwork] Full CRUD Social Media App | ReactJS, NodeJS, Django, PostgreSQL, JWT Authentication, API data integration | GitHub Repos: Front-End, Back-End

- An app to connect alumni of a school or course for continued networking and support
- Modeled after early Facebook, users can set up a profile with their contact information, create posts and comments in different conversation topics, view and add to a list of relevant events
- Users can register and login to view protected routes, and can also update or delete their own posts or comments, and update their profile information as needed

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Merchant, Trader Joe's | Acton, MA

August 2008 - Present

- Selected to train and onboard new colleagues in best practices for task efficiency, job specific technologies and time management
- Manage product inventory in 1-4 grocery categories per shift with G.O.L.D. inventory system
- Adept at assessing the needs and idiosyncrasies of customers to ensure a high-quality customer experience
- Positively impact work culture through attentiveness and empathy toward colleagues and customers
- Proficiency in de-escalation and empowerment to efficiently turn negative situations positive

Counter Staff, Haven Body Arts | Northampton, MA

April 2011 - January 2012

- Assisted clients in making an educated jewelry selection based on health and safety criteria as well as personal style choices
- Provided a calm and reassuring presence for clients to instill a feeling of confidence in the body piercing professionals
- Followed proper procedures for maintaining the integrity of sterile tools and jewelry to be used on clients
- Maintained a vast inventory of jewelry in a wide variety of sizes, styles and materials to ensure each client can find the piece best suited to their individual needs
- Ensured each client understood and properly filled out all forms provided to them in order to meet both legal and health and safety guidelines

Mobile Energy Team, Red Bull | Northampton, MA

October 2006 - July 2007

- Created a personal experience for clients by introducing them to the product in a relevant setting
- Planned and implemented events each day to increase brand exposure
- Acted as the face of the brand for public events and promotional opportunities

EDUCATION

GENERAL ASSEMBLY | REMOTE

Software Engineering Immersive

January 2022 - July 2022

Full-stack software engineering immersive student in an intensive, 24-week, 450+ hour program focused on product development fundamentals, object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and team collaboration strategies. Developed a portfolio of individual and group projects.

UNIVERSITY OF MASSACHUSETTS | AMHERST, MA

Isenberg School of Management
Bachelor of Business Administration in Marketing, Management

September 2004 - May 2008